HAMZA SHAIKH

Developer

CONTACT

- +91 9604195840
- ✓ shaikhhamzasaleem960@gmail.com
- **Q** 3043, Sobha Orion, Parge Nagar, Kondhwa, Pune
- https://hamza960.github.io/Pers onal-Portfolio-new/

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a skilled full-stack and frontend developer with 4 years of experience, specializing in React.js. I excel in understanding customer requirements, prioritizing tasks, and delivering projects on time or ahead of schedule. My strong communication skills and commitment to quality ensure client satisfaction in every project I undertake.

EDUCATION

2018-2021 ABEDA INAMDAR SENIOR COLLEGE

BCA Science

2016-2018 POONA COLLEGE

Science Stream

SKILLS

- ·HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- ·Bootstrap
- SCSS
- ·Responsive Design
- React JS
- ∙Redux
- React Redux
- Redux toolkit
- Laravel
- ·Node JS
- ·Express JS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hexaware Technologies

JULY 2024 - CURRENT

Developer

- Software customization using JavaScript and Esker scripting tool based on business requirements
- Technical documentation
- · Agile Methodology
- · Code versioning Git
- VS Code
- · Customer interaction
- Team collaboration
- Troubleshooting
- I have been trained under the AP (Accounts Payable) and OM (Order Management) modules of Esker and have performed different customizations and enhancements for different customers.
- I have trained my colleagues for node.js and API creation

IT Gurus Software

JAN 2022 - MAR 2024

Developer

- Created enhancements and customizations in the Access Expense App using React.js.
- Created and maintained UI components using React functional component
- · Followed agile methodology like scrum
- · Used code versioning tools like git and SVN
- Handled tasks in JIRA
- Made several static websites using HTML CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap.

HAMZA SHAIKH

Developer

SKILLS

- ·PHP
- Performance Optimization
- ·Code Optimization
- Troubleshooting
- ·Code Versioning techniques
- ·Git
- ·GitHub
- JIRA
- Agile Methodologies
- ·SCRUM
- Documentation
- SVN
- · UI / UX Design
- MySQL
- MongoDB

LANGUAGES

English: FluentHindi: FluentMarathi: FluentUrdu: Fluent

WORK EXPERIENCE

Innothoughts Systems

AUG 2021 - DEC 2021

- Built and maintained reusable react components and responsive UI using bootstrap, designed the UI from Scratch based on the design provided.
- Used MongoDB for Data handling
- Created APIs using Node is
- Created several static websites using HTML, CSS, bootstrap and JavaScript.
- Followed agile methodology like scrum
- Code versioning tools like Git was used

SBU Solutions

May 2021 - Aug 2021

- Created and implemented React App using functional component.
- Created APIs and web applications using Laravel framework.
- Attending customer calls and gathering the requirements.
- Technical Documentations
- Troubleshooting
- Code Versioning Git

Projects I worked on

- Jamiat Halal Trust (Laravel & React.js)
- GuideMeDoc UAE (MERN stack)
- Healing Hands (HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Bootstrap)
- Socialicious (HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Bootstrap)
- Access Expense UK (React.js)
- LearnWithIP (MERN stack)
- Diamond Poultry (React.js & Laravel)
- Medcipher (HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Bootstrap)
- Dr Swapnil Maate Landing Page (HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Bootstrap)
- Mundipharma (Esker JavaScript Customization)
- Arizona Cardinals (Esker JavaScript Customization)
- IMG Academy (Esker JavaScript Customization)